SAM ROSE | ☑ hello@samrose.me ☑ 865.323.6200 😱 samrose3 🗓 samrose3

Software Engineer creating experiences for mobile and the web. I am dedicated to delivering high-quality software and promoting the discipline of user experience design.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee | KNOXVILLE, TN Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering DEC 2017 GPA 3.88 / 4.00

EXPERIENCE

IBM | JAN 2018 - CURRENT

Front End Engineer for IBM Analytics

Leading engineering and design initiatives on IBM Cloud Private for Data to better design an on-premise data platform for enterprise.

Primary responsibilities include front-end performance, design system implementation and release management, interaction design, usability testing, process engineering, and project management.

IBM | JUN 2017 - AUG 2017

Front End Developer Intern

Served as Front End Developer on an interdisciplinary team of product managers, user researchers, visual designers, and UX specialist to tackle design challenges and craft software product offerings using IBM Design Thinking methods.

Developed the initial full-stack implementations of product offerings as well as serving as a technical consultant throughout the design process.

GitLab | DEC 2016 - MAY 2017

Junior Frontend Engineer

Collaborated with remote team on developing GitLab, an online Git repository manager with a wiki, issue tracking, CI and CD. Required ability to work asynchronously with other developers and designers in different time zones.

Implemented new features into GitLab such as PDF rendering and exporting Issues as CVS. When not working on deliverables, tackled open regressions and bugs related to the front-end.

Cadre5 | MAY 2014 - DEC 2016

Software Engineer

Played key role in frontend development of Angular web app for Oak Ridge National Labs. Project involved highly customize UI and responsive design, requiring extensive knowledge of application architecture, component-based layout, and mobile design.

Designed and developed scheduling application to produce Keurig K-Cups at Keurig Green Mountain factory in Knoxville, TN.

TECHNICAL OVERVIEW

Languages	Frameworks	Tooling	Design	Interests
HTML / CSS / JS	Vue	Git	Sketch	Machine Learning
Python	React	Webpack	Web Animation	Data Visualization
Ruby	Rails	CI / CD	Design Systems	Process Design
SQL	Django	Kubernetes	Interaction Design	Agile
C++	Vuex / Redux	Docker		